So, in this lecture let's understand about Installing an Integrated Development Environment.
So, in short we call it as IDE. IDE is a software that contains all the essential tools to develop,
compile, link, and debug your code.
In some cases, you may have to integrate compiler and debugger tools to the IDE manually.
So, throughout this course we will be using Eclipse-based STM32CubeIDE which is developed by ST Microelectronics
to write, compile, debug
your embedded system applications on STM32 ARM-based microcontrollers. STM32Cube
IDE is an Eclipse-based IDE with STM32 related customization.
Let's see how to download STM32CubeIDE.
So, first of all you have to visit this link. So, this link is given in the resource section of this lecture.
So, once you go to this link so you will find Get Software section. There you can download the software
according to your machine.
So in my case, I'm using Windows based machine, so I'll be downloading Windows software. And select the
version here.
You can select the newer version which is available and then click on Get Software. Once you click on
Get Software
it will take you to the download page. And here you either have to register or if you don't want to register,
then you can download the software by simply providing your name and email address in this form.
So, go ahead and download this software and I'll see you in the next lecture.