Alright. Now let's understand what exactly is a computer program.
A program is a series of instructions that cause a computer or a microcontroller to perform a particular
task. A computer program includes more than just instructions.
It also contains data and various memory addresses on which the instructions work to perform a specific
task.
Now, let's look at different programming languages which we use in embedded systems design.
So, to write a program we have to use programming language, isn't it?
Note that, if your goal is to become an embedded system programmer, then you must be good at C or C++
programming languages or both.
Nowadays, a rust programming language also has quickly gained popularity and also becoming very much
famous in embedded programming.
C, C++, Rust, Assembly,
so these are the main programming languages which are being used in embedded systems.
The usage of Python, Micro Python, and Java are also rarely used in embedded systems code development.
Assembly level programming is very much powerful and it is still being used in various parts of the
embedded project.
So, it's not like you know a C and C++ have completely taken over the assembly level programming. A still
some part of the project is coded in assembly level programming.
Now, if you look at the survey of 2017 made by Embedded.com,
so here is a screenshot of Dan Saks presentation during the keynotes speech.
So, this video you can find on you tube. So, very much informative video you should watch it on YouTube.
If you look at this slide, you can see that 'C' is still the number 1 and highly favored programming
language for embedded systems followed by C++ and assembly. But you can also notice that usage of 'C'
may be declining. So, in future C++ and Rust programming languages also have the potential to gain
significant popularity in embedded systems programming. But still 'C' leads in embedded domain.
It is one of the most powerful high level programming languages to write programs for embedded systems.
So, you can download this survey as a PDF
if you want from Embedded.com website.
Alright. So, that gives us a motivation why we should learn 'C' programming language, because it is still
one of the leading programming languages for embedded systems.
Now let's get started with exploring the 'C' programming language.