Let's look at 'C' programming standardization and will also look at some history of 'C' programming language.
The 'C' Programming language was initially developed in AT&T labs by Professor Brian Kernighan and Dennis
Ritchie, known as K&R C.
So, during the year 1970, 'C' programming became very much popular
but without any serious standardization to the language. The non-official standard was called K&R
C, which led to many ambiguities among different compiler programmers,
and that actually led to non-portable codes.
K&R C was a first non-official 'C' standard. So, in 1989 American National Standards Institute(ANSI)
designed and approved first official 'C' standard, which is also denoted by this tag name.
And in 1990 it was approved by ISO as international standard for 'C' programming language.
So the ISO tag name is this one. So, that means the first official international standard was released
by ISO in 1990.
So that's why, it is also called as ANSI C or C89 or C90 standard.So, the language underwent few more
changes (like addition of new features, addition of new syntaxes, data types etc.) and newly updated
standard was released in 1999 under the ISO tag
this one, which is also called C99 standard in short. So, in December 2011 ISO released new
standard under this tag name, which is also called as
C11 standard. C11 supersedes the C99
standard.
So now in this course, we will be using the C11 standard which is actually compiler default with
some compiler extensions.
So, collectively we call it as a gnu11. So more on this, we'll see later. How to change the compiler
settings to mention the 'C' standard?
So, we'll cover this later.
So, note that if you have written a code using C90 standard, then it will compile without any issues
in C99 standard compilation, so that what we call is backward compatibility.
So but if you have written code using C99 standard specific features, then it may not compile
successfully in C90 compilation. So, you should keep this in mind.
But don't worry about this, so we'll see how to set the standard in the compiler later. From the next
lecture onwards
let's get started with programming.
So, let's start with the Hello world program and I'll see you in the next lecture.