Let's see some of the features of this STM32CubeIDE. In this web page they have listed
some of the key features of this IDE.
Let's understand what are the features which are important to us.
The very important thing is, it supports all the OS platforms.
Why?
Because, it is based on Eclipse.
That's why, Multi-OS support.
So that's the good news.
And the next important thing is, it comes with inbuilt cross compilers and debuggers.
You need not to download any external compilers or debuggers to integrate that with this IDE. So,
everything comes in one single bundle.
So, this IDE actually uses a GNU based C C++ compiler for ARM embedded processors.It has a several other
features like importing projects from Atollic, TrueSTUDIO, and System Workbench. And also in this IDE
you find some of the advanced debug features including SWV, which stands for a System analysis and real
time tracing which we will be using in this course. And I'll be explaining how to use SWV in the later part
of the course, and also of course you can
observe all the CPU core registers, IP registers, and also you can browse various memory locations of the
microcontroller a while you debug the code. So, everything will be covered in this course.
And another important feature of this IDE is it has inbuilt support for STM32CubeMX.
Now earlier we used to install a separate STM32CubeMX software and then we used to generate
the code
and after that we used to import that project into the eclipse software.
But with the release of this IDE that is not required.
So, it gives inbuilt support for
STM32CubeMX a for peripheral configuration and code generation, but this feature that is integrated
STM32CubeMX feature will not be used in this course.
So, you should remember that will not be using STM32CubeMX.