All right.
So now let's extract this. OK.
So, now you have to go under this folder and this is the installation script which we have to run now.
OK.
So, for that let's go to the command prompt.
I'm in that directory, and just do ls.
OK.
And let's go under this directory.
All right.
Now let's do ls. And we have to now give executable permission to this script.
OK.
For that, we have to run sudo chmod +x. OK.
and the file name.
All right.
Press Enter.
Great.
So, now let's run by using sudo ./ and the file name.
Right?
So, now it is getting installed.
So, please be patient.
All right.
So now you have to accept the license agreement,
just press space key and type
y. Right?
So and then press enter and the license will be accepted.
All right.
So now just be patient,
there you go.
The installation was successful.
Now let's go to the search box and let's search for ST
and here it is.
OK.
You can launch this application now. All right. And here it is.
So, it is asking for you to open the workspace and we are not going to open any workspace
as of now.
OK.
And we can just press Cancel here.
Great.
So, now you just installed the STM32CubeIDE on your Ubuntu machine.
Okay.
And I'll see you in the next lecture.