So, in this lecture let's understand installation of GNU Compiler Collections for host.
That means, we are going to install the GCC compiler for host.
So, note that the STM32CubeIDE which we installed in the previous video is an integrated development
environment software to develop, compile, and debug embedded applications for STM32 microcontrollers.
So, the STM32CubeIDE installation procedure which we carried out in the previous video, also
installed the GCC cross compiler for ARM Cortex Mx processors.
So, you need not to download any external cross compilers. It is already done. In this course,
we are using a same IDE, to write and compile 'C' programs for our host machine.
That is Windows, Linux, and Mac machines.
So now we need to install the compiler for our host machine, which doesn't come with the
STM32CubeIDE installation. So, that we are going to do now.
If you are using Linux or Mac, then it is very simple you just have to run few commands in order to install
the GCC compiler for your host.
So that I am going to cover later, but in the next lecture I'm going to cover how to install GCC for your
Windows machine.
It is not that straightforward because, we use GCC in windows through a tool called MinGW. MinGW stands
for Minimalist GNU tools for Windows.
So, it is actually the windows flavor of GNU tools.
So, in the next lecture I'll be covering how to install MinGW on your Windows machine,
so if you are reusing Linux or Mac machines, please skip the next video.